[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Stop!
- [GUNSHOTS]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
[METAL RODS CLANGING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
NCIA! Nobody move!
[GUNSHOTS]
- Go, go! Kill them!
- [LEVER CLICKS, POWER CUTS]
Where are you?!
Show me yourself!
[GUNSHOTS]
- [KICK LANDS]
- [BODY THUDS]
[POWER TURNS BACK ON]
Stop! Stop!
Mr. Chan, you're under arrest.
You have the right
to remain silent.
You disobeyed my orders.
You broke protocol!
You proved just how
stubborn you are!
Whatever your decision
may be, I'll accept it.
Punish me instead,
just spare my team.
Gabo's here, with the gold,
he brought it inside.
He ran off with the gold?
Let's wait and see.
Don't judge Gabo yet.
- [CAR HORN HONKS]
- [ENGINES REVVING]
Does it hurt here?
- Any pain?
- No.
[BROODING MUSIC PLAYING]
Open your mouth, please.
Stick out your tongue.
[BROODING MUSIC CONTINUES]
Please stand up. Help him up.
Hey!
Take off his clothes.
[BROODING MUSIC CONTINUES]
- Any pain here?
- No.
- Take off his pants.
- No!
- What are you doing?!
- Wait.
Mr. Chan, it's
standard procedure.
The doctor needs to make sure
you're in good condition
and check your existing injuries
before you go to custody.
You understand?
Go ahead, continue.
[GRUNTS]
[DOCTOR]
Male, conscious, and coherent.
Vital signs, stable.
- Turn to the left, Mr. Chan.
- He has a forehead abrasion.
And... a superficial laceration
on his lip.
- Turn to the right, Mr. Chan.
- But other than that,
there are no apparent
external injuries.
Okay. Thank you, Doc.
Okay, turn to the front.
- [BROODING MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Ouch!
[WHIMPERS LOUDLY]
- I'm good.
- Sir, let's clean this up.
It's fine, we're okay.
- Just take these.
- [GRUNTS SOFTLY]
Can you calm down?! You
might get high blood pressure.
If you pop a blood vessel, we'll
have to take you to the ER.
Karen, why did you guys move
without Sir Delgado's go signal?
For Sam.
To finally close the case.
Yeah, we followed our hearts
instead of our heads.
But we did what was right.
Well, you're in big trouble
with Sir Delgado then.
You could get suspended,
or worse, fired from the NCIA.
Will you stop, Ernesto? You'd
only understand our actions
if you had a co-agent
you truly cared about.
Excuse me, I do care
about my fellow agents.
- You?
- Oh boy.
Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy.
- Does it hurt?
- No, it feels good.
[PLAYFUL MUSIC PLAYING,
THEN FADES]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Everything you did will
be in the report!
You guys knew this was wrong,
didn't you?!
Didn't you?!
Yes...
Jacinto was your team leader
on the Chinatown mission.
But didn't you know...
Sir Delgado was taking her off
the gold smuggling case?!
We knew that, Ma'am Pia.
We needed to catch Mr. Chan
before he could even hide.
[SCOFFS]
And did you know this operation
you pulled was unofficial?
[SEQIOA] Ma'am Pia.
We know what we are doing.
And as a matter of fact,
we had everything under control.
I guess you really want...
...to ruin your careers, huh?
With all due respect,
Ma'am Pia...
If you had included
in your report
what Jacinto did in Chinatown,
this wouldn't have happened.
So, you're blaming me?
Is that it?
- Ma'am Pia--
- [CASTOR] Borromeo.
Don't talk back.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[PIA CLICKS TEETH]
Guys, you better wake up.
Jacinto's ship is sinking.
Don't let yourselves
drown with her.
[SIGHS DEEPLY]
This is what I was afraid of!
He's alive, isn't he?
It's nothing fatal.
You think it's okay he got shot
just because he survived?
Yes, he got shot.
So, what?
I've been shot before.
So have Victor.
This is normal
in the world we live in.
Yes, but it could
have been avoided
if you had just listened to me!
He must experience these things.
Iron doesn't become steel
until it has been through fire.
Ma'am, sir.
Doc.
How is my son?
The bullet didn't hit
any major artery.
He just needs rest.
Kindly monitor him
for any infection.
Thank you.
You're welcome, ma'am.
Thank you, Doc.
I'll have Arturo contact you.
Okay.
Jacinto.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Well? Has Sir Delgado
suspended you already?
- No.
- You sure are something.
You have the gall to risk
the lives of your comrades...
...just to make yourself
look good.
That isn't my intention.
And everything I did,
I did it for the NCIA.
Just wait for my report.
Let's see if you can still do
anything for the agency
after I submit it.
You are a Jacinto.
But...
all you have to show for
is your name.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Hi! Is there anything I missed?
Yes.
You missed the bullet
that almost killed you.
Oh, I didn't miss it.
I tried to dodge it,
but it grazed me.
Still, I was marked safe.
Hmm. For now, yes.
Let's see how long
you will be...
...safe.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [SAM SIGHS DEEPLY]
- Just ignore her.
It's not like she hasn't
done that before.
Don't let her get to you.
- Lucas.
- Ma.
Lucas, I trusted you,
but you failed.
[GRIM MUSIC PLAYING]
I'm sorry, Pa.
I'll make up for my failure.
Mariano, let him heal first.
I'll get back at them, Ma.
[LUCAS BREATHING DEEPLY]
Forget about Mr. Chan for now.
Our men will take care of it.
I'm not talking about Mr. Chan.
The one who shot me!
Why? Did you see their face?
She's from the NCIA.
The woman who arrested Victor.
- Huh?
- She's the one who shot me.
Samantha Jacinto.
[GRIM MUSIC CONTINUES]
I can't help but wonder
about the gold bars.
Where could they be now?
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
[BRIEFCASE CLICKS]
[SAM] Someone else was there.
They made it easier for us
to catch Mr. Chan.
The question is, who was it?
Could he be the same
mysterious man
who was the reason
we were able to arrest Tiger?
[PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MUSIC BECOMES STIRRING]
[STIRRING MUSIC CONTINUES]
Mr. Chan.
You are facing charges
of illegal gold mining
and money laundering.
I don't understand Tagalog.
Only English.
Okay. I'll translate it
into English for you.
Mr. Chan.
You are under investigation
for your alleged involvement
in illegal gold mining
and money laundering.
You listen to me.
I have a lot of money.
I can give you money. Gold.
You want gold?
I'll give you some!
- Tell me.
- [CHUCKLES]
How much do you want?
Let me go. No jail.
It looks like you want to add
to your charges, Mr. Chan.
Bribery.
Do you want that?
Just say it.
No, no, no, no.
Mr. Chan.
I know you can understand me.
We know that your gold came
from Victor Zafra.
So, tell me,
how deep is your involvement
in the syndicate?
No more talk!
I want my lawyer!
Do you understand?
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[ARTURO] Ma'am, our men saw
the NCIA arresting Mr. Chan.
They will definitely
use Mr. Chan
to pin this case on Victor.
We'll have a harder time
getting him out.
It was also NCIA
who shot Lucas, right?
[DEBORAH] The same agent
who arrested Victor.
Samantha Jacinto.
Well...
your past is catching up on us.
And our children are the ones
who have to pay for it.
We must do something ASAP.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[BORROMEO] Ma'am Sam is here.
- Hey, buddy.
- Sam.
[SIGHS]
Sam?
Are you alright?
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Team.
I'm sorry
for involving you in this.
I forced you into something
that I thought was right.
But what I did was wrong.
You didn't force us
into this, Sam.
[SEQIOA] I agree with Karen.
I mean, no need to apologize.
The mission was still a success.
We caught Mr. Chan, so cheer up.
[CASTOR] And besides,
we are one team.
We will continue to support
each other until the end.
[ROBER] That's right.
They'll probably understand
why we did this.
The gold smuggling case got
stronger because of what we did.
[BORROMEO] But, ma'am...
I hope Sir Delgado
doesn't suspend us.
Or fire us.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SEBASTIAN CHUCKLES]
You know,
you only made one mistake.
This is based on my opinion.
What is it?
Well, you didn't include me.
Us.
If we were there, they wouldn't
stand a chance against us.
Mm-hmm!
Seb, Rallos, sorry for not
letting you in on the mission.
Uh, Sam.
I know that you don't trust me.
Even if...
I trust you with my whole life.
Seb, it's not like that.
Things just happened
way too fast.
Plus I thought that if there
were a lot of us,
it'd be difficult to carry
the mission out.
I'll earn that trust.
I deserve it, Sam.
Some day, in every thing
that you do,
you will come to me first.
[SEBASTIAN CLICKS TONGUE]
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [UTENSILS CLINKING]
- Mmm!
It's delicious. It's good!
- Good meal.
- Yeah.
[DOOR SWINGS OPEN]
[LAWIN] Pops!
Hey, Pops.
What did I tell you?
You really can't trust Gabo.
Pops, Gabo stole all the gold
and took them home.
Why didn't you take
the gold back then?
[LAWIN] Tomas, I can't take
Gabo on my own.
Even if Uwak and I take him
on together, we won't survive.
What are we going to do now?
We'll just wait for Gabo.
He'll come around soon.
Well, we'll be waiting
for all eternity then, Pops!
He won't come for sure.
I know how his mind works.
- He's from Ginintuang Lupa!
- Yeah!
They're easily tempted!
With how valuable that gold is
he's got it all to himself now!
[ENGINE REVVING]
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
[PAPANG] In the short time
that I've known him,
I know that he has
a kind heart.
He will do the right thing.
Well, let's see about that.
[DOOR CREAKS OPEN]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
'Tang.
Gabo?
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Here's the gold.
[STIRRING MUSIC INTENSIFIES]
[STIRRING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SUITCASE LOCKS CLICKING]
[OMENG] Pops.
It's all here.
This suitcase too, Pops.
[PAPANG CHUCKLING]
My judgment of your character
is correct.
You are trustworthy.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[SUITCASES CLOSING]
[GLOOMY MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR OPENS, SQUEAKS]
Sir, you didn't suspend Jacinto?
[SCOFFING]
Sir, you're too soft on her.
The law is the law.
If someone breaks it,
they must be held accountable!
[THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING]
Not everything is
black and white, Pia.
There are things that we...
...do that are often not
in accordance with the law.
But they're necessary.
Necessary?
[THRILLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
What's necessary is for you
to make a decision now.
Even at the cost
of your favorite agent.
[HUFFS]
Just how long will you keep
taking Jacinto's side?
[THRILLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
Remember.
Your weakness becomes
the agency's weakness.
[THRILLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [FOOTSTEPS RETREATING]
- [DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[PHONE RINGING]
[PHONE BEEPS]
[THRILLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
Ricardo.
What do you need?
We need to talk,
but not on the phone.
Let's meet.
[MUSIC BECOMES SUSPENSEFUL]
Okay. When?
Right now.
At this hour?
Just send me
the meeting location.
[PHONE BEEPS]
[LINE DROPPED]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[PHONE CLATTERS]
What's your plan?
Talking won't work
on Ricardo anymore.
We need to negotiate
the hard way.
[MUSIC FADING]
- [FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
- [SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
Pops, here's the money.
[LATCHES SNAPPING OPEN]
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MONEY RUSTLING]
Gabo.
That's for you, Gabo.
[GABO]
Tatang, thank you so much.
I told you already.
Just call me Pops.
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[ENVELOPE RUSTLING]
[CHUCKLES AWKWARDLY]
Pops, I think you gave me
too much money.
Our deal was only 100,000 pesos.
Well, consider it a reward
for your loyalty.
[EXHALES SOFTLY]
Thank you so, so much.
I desperately need the money.
Pops, I'll get going.
My father needs surgery now.
Goodbye. Thanks again.
[MUSIC FADING]
[FOOTSTEPS RETREATING]
So, what now?
Feeling embarrassed, huh?
Because you thought Gabo
would run off with the gold.
You assumed he would do
something bad.
[OMENG] During our time
with Gabo behind bars,
we witnessed
what he was really like.
He has principles.
He knows what's right and wrong.
[LOW CHUCKLE]
Luck!
Just pure luck!
Sooner or later,
his true colors will come out.
[LAWIN] That Gabo...
If he doesn't die on a mission,
he'll find a way to escape
and turn his back on the group.
Just like the other released
prisoners before him.
Gabo won't do the things
you're imagining.
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
- [KEYS JINGLING]
- [ENGINE TURNS ON]
[ENGINE REVVING]
How did you get
my number?
[WOMAN] We heard
that you needed money.
If you're going
to give us money,
then why do we have
to send you 5,000 pesos?
[WOMAN]
So I can start processing it.
Just do what I said.
Do you want the money or not?
Nitwit!
You're seriously
trying to scam me?
[SCOFFS]
We're poor,
we're struggling
to pay hospital bills,
and now you're trying
to scam me?!
You can't fool me!
You're an animal.
May your soul burn in hell!
You animal!
Auntie!
- [GABO] Hey.
- Gabo.
- I have the money.
- [BETCHAY GASPS]
For Papa's medicine
and his surgery.
Thank you!
Thank you so much
for keeping your promise!
Gabo, where did you
get the money?
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
[BETCHAY] Oh, please.
Now isn't the time for that.
What matters is that we can
now pay for Rudy's surgery.
Come on.
Let's go to your father.
Let's go. Hurry.
- [MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [MACHINE BEEPING]
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Gabo,
thank you for what you did.
I won't let anything bad
happen to Papa.
We've been separated
for so long.
I'll do everything
to keep him alive.
Where did you get the money?
What was the job?
[MAMENG] Betchay! [SNIFFLES]
Are you going to start
an argument again?
I found a job, that's it.
What is it?
What kind of job?
Is it legal?
Someone asked me...
to get something.
And whatever it is,
it's none of your business.
What thing?
What was the thing
they asked you to get?
What did you do?
[MAMENG SOBBING] Betchay!
That's enough.
What matters is we got
the money because of Gabo.
We were able to pay
for Rudy's surgery.
[BETCHAY SIGHS EXASPERATEDLY]
Pops.
You seem happy with
how Gabo's mission turned out.
Tomas,
Gabo just proved
that Pops can trust him.
He didn't deny
that for a moment he was tempted
to run away with the gold.
In a moment of temptation,
a person's true character
and principles show.
[DOOR OPENS]
Are you Rudy Magtibay's family?
Yes, that's us.
How's my father?
- The surgery was successful.
- [BETCHAY CRIES]
[SURGEON] Let's just wait
for him to wake up.
[BETCHAY CRYING]
Thank you so, so much, Doc.
Thank you.
[BETCHAY, MAMENG CRYING]
[MAMENG] Thank you.
[ROUSING MUSIC PLAYING]
[PAPANG] Gabo is ready.
If there's anyone who has
to face a bigger decision,
it's Gabo.
- Let's drink to that.
- [GLASSES CLINK]
[ROUSING MUSIC CONTINUES]
Whether they're
businessmen, politicians,
or treasure hunters that
secretly dig up the ground
in different parts
of provinces,
and when they return,
they suddenly became rich.
From what I've heard, sir,
it's tons and tons of gold.
- What is that?
- A treasure map.
I feel bad for you, Gabo.
You shouldn't have
to live like this.
Remember when you were a child?
I do, Pa.
- [KID CRYING]
- Gabriel, listen to me.
- [GUNSHOT]
- Listen to Mommy, okay?
I remember everything.
This job Umali asked us to do,
if we fail,
it'll be a big loss for us.
I won't fight back, boss!
It's not the reporter
who caught us.
- Who is it?
- [BLOWS LAND]
We don't know him.
How many were they?
He's alone.
I'm asking you
so answer me properly!
The admin put you on
preventive suspension.
The next time you do
something to tarnish my name,
I won't kick you
out of the house,
I'll disown you.
Rudy!
Show yourself!
I need to find that cop.
Mommy loves you so much.
He needs to pay
for what he did to my mother.
- Get out of here, hurry!
- [GUNSHOTS]
Have mercy on my family!
Just take me!
You animal!
And for what he did to you.
You really chose
that filthy Rudy!
Please don't hurt my son
and my husband!
- [GUNSHOT]
- Find out
where more of the gold
is hidden.
He's the reason
why we're struggling.
I need to find him!
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVS]
[BODY THUDS]